Privacy Policy of **My Study Life**
===================================

My Study Life collects some Personal Data from its Users.

This document can be printed for reference by using the print command in the settings of any browser.

Policy summary
--------------

Personal Data processed for the following purposes and using the following services:
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

* * ### Analytics
        
        * ### Google Analytics (Universal Analytics)
            
            Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data

    * ### Data transfer outside of the UK
        
        * ### Data transfer abroad based on standard contractual clauses (UK)
            
            Personal Data: various types of Data

    * ### Displaying content from external platforms
        
        * ### Gravatar
            
            Personal Data: email address; Usage Data
            
        * ### Google Fonts
            
            Personal Data: Trackers; Usage Data

    * ### Heat mapping and session recording
        
        * ### Hotjar Heat Maps & Recordings
            
            Personal Data: Tracker; Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Hosting and backend infrastructure
        
        * ### Microsoft Azure
            
            Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Infrastructure monitoring
        
        * ### Raygun
            
            Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms
        
        * ### Facebook Like button and social widgets, LinkedIn button and social widgets and Twitter Tweet button and social widgets
            
            Personal Data: Tracker; Usage Data
            
        * ### YouTube button and social widgets
            
            Personal Data: Usage Data

    * ### Managing contacts and sending messages
        
        * ### Sendgrid
            
            Personal Data: email address

    * ### Managing support and contact requests
        
        * ### Zendesk
            
            Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Platform services and hosting
        
        * ### WordPress.com
            
            Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Registration and authentication
        
        * ### Google OAuth
            
            Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
            
        * ### Facebook Authentication
            
            Personal Data: Tracker; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
            
        * ### Further information about Personal Data

    * ### Registration and authentication provided directly by My Study Life
        
        * ### Direct registration
            
            Personal Data: email address; first name; last name; password

    * ### SPAM protection
        
        * ### Google reCAPTCHA
            
            Personal Data: answers to questions; clicks; keypress events; motion sensor events; mouse movements; scroll position; touch events; Tracker; Usage Data

    * ### User database management
        
        * ### HubSpot CRM
            
            Personal Data: email address; phone number; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

Further information about the processing of Personal Data
---------------------------------------------------------

* * ### Business Transfers
        
        If we are involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, we may transfer your Personal Data and other User data. In such case, your information would remain subject to this Privacy Policy until such time as this Privacy Policy is updated.
        
    * ### Unique device identification
        
        My Study Life may track Users by storing a unique identifier of their device, for analytics purposes or for storing Users' preferences.

Contact information
-------------------

* * ### Owner and Data Controller
        
        **My Study Life Ltd (MSL)**, a company registered in England and Wales with company number 09070277 whose registered address is 40 The Glades, Aldridge, Walsall, West Midlands, WS9 8RN, United Kingdom.
        
        **Owner contact email:** support@mystudylife.com

Full policy
-----------

Owner and Data Controller
-------------------------

**My Study Life Ltd (MSL)**, a company registered in England and Wales with company number 09070277 whose registered address is 40 The Glades, Aldridge, Walsall, West Midlands, WS9 8RN, United Kingdom.

**Owner contact email:** support@mystudylife.com

Types of Data collected
-----------------------

Among the types of Personal Data that My Study Life collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Tracker; first name; last name; email address; password; Usage Data; phone number; various types of Data; answers to questions; clicks; keypress events; motion sensor events; mouse movements; scroll position; touch events.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using My Study Life.  
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by My Study Life is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for My Study Life to provide its services. In cases where My Study Life specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools — by My Study Life or by the owners of third-party services used by My Study Life serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through My Study Life.

Mode and place of processing the Data
-------------------------------------

### Methods of processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of My Study Life (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.  
  
Depending on the User's location, data transfers may involve transferring the User's Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

### Retention time

Unless specified otherwise in this document, Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for and may be retained for longer due to applicable legal obligation or based on the Users’ consent.

The purposes of processing
--------------------------

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Service, comply with its legal obligations, respond to enforcement requests, protect its rights and interests (or those of its Users or third parties), detect any malicious or fraudulent activity, as well as the following: Registration and authentication, Registration and authentication provided directly by My Study Life, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Infrastructure monitoring, Managing support and contact requests, Analytics, Managing contacts and sending messages, User database management, Heat mapping and session recording, Data transfer outside of the UK, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Platform services and hosting, Displaying content from external platforms and SPAM protection.

For specific information about the Personal Data used for each purpose, the User may refer to the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data”.

Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data
-------------------------------------------------------

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

* ### Analytics
    
    The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.
    
    #### Google Analytics (Universal Analytics) (Google LLC)
    
    Google Analytics (Universal Analytics) is a web analysis service provided by Google LLC (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of My Study Life, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
    Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.
    
    In order to understand Google's use of Data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).
    
    Personal Data processed: Cookies; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://business.safety.google/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).
    
* ### Displaying content from external platforms
    
    This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of My Study Life and interact with them.  
    This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.
    
    #### Gravatar (Aut O’Mattic A8C Ireland Ltd.)
    
    Gravatar is an image visualization service provided by Aut O’Mattic A8C Ireland Ltd. that allows My Study Life to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.  
    Please note that if Gravatar images are used for comment forms, the commenter's email address or parts of it may be sent to Gravatar - even if the commenter has not signed up for that service.
    
    Personal Data processed: email address; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/).
    
    #### Google Fonts (Google Ireland Limited)
    
    Google Fonts is a typeface visualization service provided by Google Ireland Limited that allows My Study Life to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
    
    Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).
    
* ### Heat mapping and session recording
    
    Heat mapping services are used to display the areas of My Study Life that Users interact with most frequently. This shows where the points of interest are. These services make it possible to monitor and analyze web traffic and keep track of User behavior.  
    Some of these services may record sessions and make them available for later visual playback.
    
    #### Hotjar Heat Maps & Recordings (Hotjar Ltd.)
    
    Hotjar is a session recording and heat mapping service provided by Hotjar Ltd.  
    Hotjar honors generic „Do Not Track” headers. This means the browser can tell its script not to collect any of the User's data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. Find Hotjar’s [opt-out information here](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).
    
    Personal Data processed: Tracker; Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: Malta – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).
    
* ### Hosting and backend infrastructure
    
    This type of service has the purpose of hosting Data and files that enable My Study Life to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of My Study Life. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.
    
    #### Microsoft Azure (Microsoft Corporation)
    
    Microsoft Azure is a hosting service provided by Microsoft Corporation.
    
    Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: United Kingdom – [Privacy Policy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/PrivacyStatement).
    
* ### Infrastructure monitoring
    
    This type of service allows My Study Life to monitor the use and behavior of its components so its performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved.  
    Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, whose function is to filter the activities of My Study Life.
    
    #### Raygun (Mindscape Limited)
    
    Raygun is a monitoring service provided by Mindscape Limited.
    
    Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: New Zealand – [Privacy Policy](https://raygun.com/privacy).
    
* ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms
    
    This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of My Study Life.  
    The interaction and information obtained through My Study Life are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
    This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.  
    It is recommended to log out from the respective services in order to make sure that the processed data on My Study Life isn’t being connected back to the User’s profile.
    
    #### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook Ireland Ltd)
    
    The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook Ireland Ltd
    
    Personal Data processed: Tracker; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).
    
    #### LinkedIn button and social widgets (LinkedIn Corporation)
    
    The LinkedIn button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the LinkedIn social network provided by LinkedIn Corporation.
    
    Personal Data processed: Tracker; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy).
    
    #### Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (X Corp.)
    
    The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.
    
    Personal Data processed: Tracker; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy).
    
    #### YouTube button and social widgets (Google Ireland Limited)
    
    The YouTube button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the YouTube social network provided by Google Ireland Limited.
    
    Personal Data processed: Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).
    
* ### Managing contacts and sending messages
    
    This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.  
    These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.
    
    #### Sendgrid (Sendgrid)
    
    Sendgrid is an email address management and message sending service provided by Sendgrid Inc.
    
    Personal Data processed: email address.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy/).
    
* ### Managing support and contact requests
    
    This type of service allows My Study Life to manage support and contact requests received via email or by other means, such as the contact form.  
    The Personal Data processed depend on the information provided by the User in the messages and the means used for communication (e.g. email address).
    
    #### Zendesk (Zendesk, Inc.)
    
    Zendesk is a support and contact request management service provided by Zendesk Inc.
    
    Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/).
    
* ### Platform services and hosting
    
    These services have the purpose of hosting and running key components of My Study Life, therefore allowing the provision of My Study Life from within a unified platform. Such platforms provide a wide range of tools to the Owner – e.g. analytics, user registration, commenting, database management, e-commerce, payment processing – that imply the collection and handling of Personal Data.  
    Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.
    
    #### WordPress.com (Aut O’Mattic A8C Ireland Ltd.)
    
    WordPress.com is a platform provided by Aut O’Mattic A8C Ireland Ltd. that allows the Owner to build, run and host My Study Life.
    
    Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/).
    
* ### Registration and authentication
    
    By registering or authenticating, Users allow My Study Life to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.  
    Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, My Study Life will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for registration or identification purposes.
    
    #### Google OAuth
    
    Google OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by Google LLC or by Google Ireland Limited, depending on how the Owner manages the Data processing, and is connected to the Google network.
    
    Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy); Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).
    
    #### Facebook Authentication (Meta Platforms, Inc.)
    
    Facebook Authentication is a registration and authentication service provided by Meta Platforms, Inc. and is connected to the Facebook social network.
    
    Personal Data processed: Tracker; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/help/405977429438260).
    
    #### Further information about Personal Data
    
    Users declare themselves to be adult according to their applicable legislation. Minors may use My Study Life only with the assistance of a parent or guardian. Under no circumstance persons under the age of 16 may use My Study Life.  

* ### Registration and authentication provided directly by My Study Life
    
    By registering or authenticating, Users allow My Study Life to identify them and give them access to dedicated services. The Personal Data is collected and stored for registration or identification purposes only. The Data collected are only those necessary for the provision of the service requested by the Users.
    
    #### Direct registration (My Study Life)
    
    The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to My Study Life.
    
    Personal Data processed: email address; first name; last name; password.
    
* ### SPAM protection
    
    This type of service analyzes the traffic of My Study Life, potentially containing Users' Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.
    
    #### Google reCAPTCHA (Google Ireland Limited)
    
    Google reCAPTCHA is a SPAM protection service provided by Google Ireland Limited.  
    The use of reCAPTCHA is subject to the Google [privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and [terms of use](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/).
    
    In order to understand Google's use of Data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).
    
    Personal Data processed: answers to questions; clicks; keypress events; motion sensor events; mouse movements; scroll position; touch events; Tracker; Usage Data.
    
    Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://business.safety.google/privacy/).
    
* ### User database management
    
    This type of service allows the Owner to build user profiles by starting from an email address, a personal name, or other information that the User provides to My Study Life, as well as to track User activities through analytics features. This Personal Data may also be matched with publicly available information about the User (such as social networks' profiles) and used to build private profiles that the Owner can display and use for improving My Study Life.  
    Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails based on specific actions performed on My Study Life.
    
    #### HubSpot CRM (HubSpot, Inc.)
    
    HubSpot CRM is a User database management service provided by HubSpot, Inc.
    
    Personal Data processed: email address; phone number; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
    
    Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy).

Further information about the processing of Personal Data
---------------------------------------------------------

* ### Business Transfers
    
    If we are involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, we may transfer your Personal Data and other User data. In such case, your information would remain subject to this Privacy Policy until such time as this Privacy Policy is updated.
    
* ### Unique device identification
    
    My Study Life may track Users by storing a unique identifier of their device, for analytics purposes or for storing Users' preferences.

Cookie Policy
-------------

My Study Life uses Trackers. To learn more, Users may consult the [Cookie Policy](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/70328380/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy").

Further Information for Users
-----------------------------

### Legal basis of processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

* Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes.
* provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
* processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
* processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;
* processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.

### Further information about retention time

Unless specified otherwise in this document, Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for and may be retained for longer due to applicable legal obligation or based on the Users’ consent.

Therefore:

* Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
* Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to fulfil a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.  
  
Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right of access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

### The rights of Users based on the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following, to the extent permitted by law:

* **Withdraw their consent at any time.** Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
* **Object to processing of their Data.** Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent.
* **Access their Data.** Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
* **Verify and seek rectification.** Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
* **Restrict the processing of their Data.** Users have the right to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.
* **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.** Users have the right to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
* **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.** Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance.
* **Lodge a complaint.** Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis for Data transfers abroad including to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

#### Details about the right to object to processing

**Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.**

**Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time, free of charge and without providing any justification. Where the User objects to processing for direct marketing purposes, the Personal Data will no longer be processed for such purposes. To learn whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.**

#### How to exercise these rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. Such requests are free of charge and will be answered by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month, providing Users with the information required by law. Any rectification or erasure of Personal Data or restriction of processing will be communicated by the Owner to each recipient, if any, to whom the Personal Data has been disclosed unless this proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort. At the Users’ request, the Owner will inform them about those recipients.

### Transfer of Personal Data outside of the United Kingdom

#### Data transfer abroad based on standard contractual clauses (UK)

If this is the legal basis, the transfer of Personal Data from the UK to third countries is carried out by the Owner according to “standard contractual clauses” provided by the European Commission.

This means that Data recipients have committed to process Personal Data in compliance with the data protection standards set forth by EU data protection legislation, which are recognized as valid also under UK law. For further information, Users are requested to contact the Owner through the contact details provided in the present document.

Additional information about Data collection and processing
-----------------------------------------------------------

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of My Study Life or the related Services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, My Study Life may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, My Study Life and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with My Study Life (System logs) or use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by notifying its Users on this page and possibly within My Study Life and/or - as far as technically and legally feasible - sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.  
  
Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required.

### Definitions and legal references

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically through My Study Life (or third-party services employed in My Study Life), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use My Study Life, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using My Study Life who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

#### Data Subject

The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Processor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of My Study Life. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of My Study Life.

#### My Study Life (or this Application)

The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

#### Service

The service provided by My Study Life as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

#### European Union (or EU)

Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.

#### Cookie

Cookies are Trackers consisting of small sets of data stored in the User's browser.

#### Tracker

Tracker indicates any technology - e.g Cookies, unique identifiers, web beacons, embedded scripts, e-tags and fingerprinting - that enables the tracking of Users, for example by accessing or storing information on the User’s device.

* * *

#### Legal information

This privacy policy relates solely to My Study Life, if not stated otherwise within this document.

Latest update: August 14, 2023

This document has been created with the iubenda [Privacy and Cookie Policy Generator](https://www.iubenda.com/en/privacy-and-cookie-policy-generator). See also the [Terms and Conditions Generator](https://www.iubenda.com/en/terms-and-conditions-generator). [iubenda](https://www.iubenda.com/en/privacy-and-cookie-policy-generator) hosts this content and only collects [the Personal Data strictly necessary](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/65675001) for it to be provided.
